Web accessibility is a legal requirement,
but most open source projects never get audited.
Manual testing is slow, expensive,
and rarely done.
a11y-forge changes that.
It is an autonomous scanner that checks any
GitHub repo against WCAG standards in seconds.
Here is how it works. Paste any public
GitHub repository URL, like this one, and click Scan.
a11y-forge pulls the source tree via the GitHub API,
runs 12 static WCAG checks across HTML, JSX, CSS, and Vue files.
And scores the repo from A-plus to F.
The progress bar shows each stage.
Scanning, prioritizing violations by impact,
and generating results.
Results are shown immediately. The score card
gives you a clear grade with a breakdown of violations by type.
Each violation shows the file, line number,
severity, and a confidence score.
The screen reader preview simulates how these
issues affect assistive technology users.
You can drill into every finding
to understand exactly what needs to be fixed.
The documentation covers everything you need,
quick start guide, full API reference with curl examples.
And a detailed scanner reference showing all
12 WCAG check types from color contrast to keyboard traps.
The project includes HTML and PDF report generation,
and SVG badge creation.
a11y-forge is open source, built during
OpenAI Build Week 2026 using Codex CLI.
The runtime uses OpenAI GPT-5.6 to intelligently
group violations by user impact.
Codex accelerated development with conversational coding.
Try it yourself. Paste any public repo URL
and see your score in seconds.
Every open source project
deserves to be accessible.